我能加入你們的創業公司嗎？
Can I be part of your start-up?
為什麼？
Why?
什麼為什麼？
Why. as in?
你們都是工程師
You all are engineers
需要一個MBA
You need an MBA
納文來過電話
Naveen had called
尤吉和納文已經辭職了
Yogi and Naveen have quit their jobs and...
正在計畫開始創業
are planning a start up.
我覺得你應該加入他們
I feel you should join them
不管怎樣，你得和爸爸談談這件事
Anyhow, you have to speak to dad regarding this
我真的很想參與進來
I really want to be part of this
除非你能解決他們的問題
Unless you don't solve one of their problems
否則他們就不需要你
they don't need you
我認識一個程序員，他三年級了
I know a coder, he is in 3rd year
讓他加入吧，相信我，他會很棒的
Let's get him onboard. Trust me. He'll rock!
我研究過你的想法
I looked into your idea
是個好想法
It's quite interesting actually
但是，我還冇有給你發郵件
But, I haven't mailed you anything yet
郵件隱私是個神話，朋友
Privacy on mail is a myth, my friend.
我想我們需要傑圖
I think we need Jeetu
你覺得我們需要傑圖嗎？
You think we need jeetu?
我們需要傑圖
We need Jeetu.
我不能參加了，對不起
I'll not be able to join. Sorry!
你為什麼這麼怕你爸爸？
Why are you so scared of your Dad?
我能解決你的問題
I can solve your problem
我可以給你你需要的東西
I can give you something which you need.
我可以給你傑圖
I can give you Jeetu.
直到你找到第一筆投資
Untill you find an investment
由我來支付傑圖的工資
I'll pay for Jeetu's salary
幹杯
Cheers!
我們有四個人了
and then "There were Four".
好的！幹杯！
Ok. Cheers! Cheers! Cheers!
要有勇氣追隨自己的心聲和直覺，
它們在某種程度上知道你想成為的樣子
你們的想法很好
Your idea is very good.
我要去美國
I am going to U.S
等我從美國回來
As soon as I am back from U.S
我們將啓動投資程序
We will start the investment process
太好了
Great!...
好的
ok
真不錯
That's..
哇.
wow..
那麼，西山
So, zeeshan!
你什麼時候回來？
When do you return?
我回到了2016年11月
I am back in november 2016
2016年11月 ？
November 2016..?
是啊，有事要忙
Yeah.. got some work
但是你們不用擔心
But you guys don't worry
一旦我回來，我們就會完成投資並開始工作
A soon as I am back, we'll complete the funding and start the work
記住我說的
and mark my words
2030年第三季度
By quarter 3, 2030!
你將成為垂直行業的第一名
You will be number 1 in your verticle
2030年？
2030?
是的2030年
Yes.. 2030!
你必須理解風險投資者的思維
You have to understand and get into the mind of the VC
他們都是有錢人
they are all very rich guys
你們要穿得正式一點
you have to suit up a little bit
看起來更專業一點
You have to look a little professional
老闆! 我覺得這都是胡說八道
Boss! I think all that is bullshit!
下次開會時穿 t 恤和拖鞋
Next time wear a t-shirt and slippers to meeting
把腳放在桌子上，告訴他
Keep your feet on the table and tell him
開張支票，不然我就走了
write a cheque, or else I am leaving moth*rf**ker
自信是關鍵
Confidence is the key!
因此，一旦獲得足夠的用戶，我們就計劃籌集第二輪資金
So, once we acquire enough users, we plan to raise a second round
我們甚至可能隻做移動端，就像Flat-Chat!
We might even go mobile only. Just like Flat-Chat!
你覺得怎麼樣？
So, What do you think?
高拉夫
Gaurav!
哈恩
Haan!
好的，等一下
yes. One sec
你們都是2011年畢業的對吧？
Guys, you all are from 2011 batch. Right?
太好了
yes!
你們認識莎娜·奧貝羅伊嗎？
Do you guys know Shaina Oberoi?
莎娜·奧貝羅伊？
Shaina Oberoi?
你們有她的電話嗎？
Do you guys have her number?
冇有嗎？
No?
你們需要多少資金？
How much funding do you need?
你們在兩年半的時間裏把公司運營的很好
You have set it up well in two and a half years.
投資者非常看好外賣業務
Investors were very excited about the idea of delivering Indian food to homes
而且價格實惠
and its very affordable
你現在吃的這頓飯要花435塊錢
The meal that you are eating now costs Rs. 435
太酷了，三份餐隻要435
Cool. Rs.435 for 3 plates.
435塊錢
Its Rs.435!
我有400
I have Rs.400
要自信，把你的腳放在桌子上
Be confident, place your foot on the table
我就給你資金
I'll give you the funding.
就現在
like Now!
專業一點
Be professional
給我點自信
Show me some Confidence!
你在想什麼？
What are you thinking?
太好了
Yes!
這還差不多，老大
That's more like it. Boss!
你在幹什麼？
What are you doing?
你拿不到我的錢
You will not get my money and
我會保證不會有人給你融資
I will make sure no body funds you in Hiranandaani.
你不能把腳擡起來
You don't keep your foot up.
他會的，他為什麼不呢？
He will. How will he not?
我在矽穀待了17年
I lived in the silicon valley for 17 years
我在那裏投資了差不多5家公司
I have invested in like 5 companies there
但是在印度
But India
泥土的芬芳把我帶到了這個國家
The fragrance of soil has dragged me to this country.
你知道，我想在印度做一些事情
You know, I want do something Indian
我們將打造印度的優步
we will make India's Uber
我們稱之為印度步
We call it "Induber".
你懂我的意思了吧
You getting what Iam saying!
明白嗎
you see..
為什麼你的團隊裏冇有女性？
Why don't you have any females in your team?
你認為女人和男人不同？
You think woman are not on par with men
我白手起家創辦了佐波羅
I started Zorpolo from scratch
今天，市值五仟萬
and today, it's worth 50 f**king million
你們為什麼冇有女性聯合創始人？
Why don't you have any female co-founders?
來和我一起唱，快點，怎麼了？
Come on join me.. come on.. what's wrong?
唱起來
come on.. come on..
融資的過程就好似一場摩訶婆羅多之戰
Getting a funding is equal to fighting the battle of Mahabharatha
雖然班度五子有五個人
Pandavas were 5 of them, though.
為了贏得這場戰爭，你們需要什麼？
Now to win this war, what do you guys need?
激情
Passion
承諾
Commitment
和奉獻精神
and Dedication
這是一個比喻
It was retorical
問問我們需要什麼？
Ask what is needed?
需要什麼，先生？
What is needed Sir?
我們需要什裏·克裏希納（印度神話中足智多謀的英雄）
We need Shree Krishna!
告訴我，你們中間誰是阿俊？
Tell me, who is Arjun among you guys?
阿俊？
Arjun?
應該是傑圖吧? 我應該是尤迪斯提爾
should be Jeetu? I can be Yudistir.
我從不說謊
No Iam Yudistir, I never lie
你是比姆? 不，我是比姆
You are Bheem? No.. Dibs on Bheem.
你是薩哈傑夫
You are Sehdev
你是比姆？
You are Bheem?
納文，對，就是納文
Naveen.. ya Naveen
是的，就我吧，我是阿俊
Ya..I think it's me. Iam Arjun.
你好，Arjun
Hello Arjun
啊
Ah..
1972年
In 1972
我父親在比卡內爾的街上開了一家小店
my gradfather started a small bhujiya shop on the streets of Bikaner
一個小商店
a small shop
到了今天
and today
無論是早餐與喝茶或啤酒搭配小吃
Weather its breakfast with tea or snacks with beer
人們隻認準我們的品牌，
it's only our brand, that people use
25年來，我們一直是市場的領導者
It's been 25 years, we are leading the market
我們還上了上個月《財富》雜誌的封麵
also we were on the cover page of last month's Fortune magazine.
盡管如此
Despite of all this
你知道人們在背後怎麼稱呼我們嗎？
Do you know what people call us behind our back?
他們說你什麼？
What do they say?
佈吉亞瓦拉（臭名昭著的印度食品品牌）
Bhujiyawaala!
這就是你想擴張到不同領域的原因嗎？
So that's why you want to expand to different sectors?
你越來越明白了
You are catching on..
我要把我的錢投資在新的冒險上
I am putting my money on new ventures
你們的産品很令人興奮
Your product is very exciting
非常適合我們的多樣化經營
Perfect for our diversification.
我想在你們身上投資
I want to invest in you guys
太好了，加裏
That's great Gary
實際上我們想稀釋15% 到20% 的股權
we actually wanted to dilute 15 to 20% of our equity
融資在120萬到160萬之間
for around 1.2 to 1.6
你們來決定金額
You guys decide the number
我來決定股權結構
I' ll decide the equity
我至少要51%
I want atleast 51%
但是先生，51% 的股份就等於你成了我們公司的老闆
But sir 51% practically makes you the owner of the company
公司？
Company?
你是說... 你們四個？
You mean.. four of you?
哈？
haan?
如果你們有一個人生病了，就連桌麻將都湊不齊
If one falls sick, you won't be having a proper teams to play carrom
還公司呢
Company!
你們的市場價格
Amount that you're asking for in the market
乘以4
multiplied by 4
再加上我的品牌
plus my brand
我的人脈
My contacts
還有辦公室
Plus new office space
這完全不是一筆壞交易
Its not a bad deal at all
先生，您能降低到30-35% 嗎
Sir can we negotiate somewhere around 30-35%
我不是來買菜的，混蛋
I am not selling vegetables, you As*h*le
那個…… 加裏，這是一個非常睏難的決定
Ah! Gary, but this is a very difficult decision
我們會仔細考慮，然後告訴你
we will think over it and let you know
51% 已經很多了
like 51% is a lot
克裏斯克先生曾經問過親人阿俊
Shree Kriskna had asked Arjun, the blood of his own family members
我隻是想要更多的股權
I am just asking for a little more stake
冇其他的了
nothing much.
我們星期天再談
Will talk about it on Sunday
帕斯
Parth.
帕斯？
Parth?
我叫納文
Naveen.
帕斯
Parth!
對不起! 對不起! 對不起... 對不起
Sorry! Sorry! Sorry... Sorry.
不用，你自己走吧
No no.. Please.
走啊
Go on..
我不想拖你的後腿
I don't want to hold you back.
不，我在考慮加裏的提議
No.. I was thinking about Gary's proposal..
納文
Naveen!
你知道嗎，我們現在差不多一周才見一次麵
Do you realise we, meet like once a week now.
我去你家的時候你都很忙
You'll be busy when I come to your place
你就不能和我好好聊5分鍾嗎？
Can't you talk to me for 5 minutes properly?
對不起，對不起
I'm sorry. sorry!
你不覺得這些天你說對不起太頻繁了嗎？
Don't you think you have been saying sorry too often these days?
對不..
Iam sor....
是啊，最近我搞砸了很多事情
Yeah maybe I am screwing up a lot these days
我真的很抱歉
I am really sorry
納文，這樣不行
Naveen, Its not gonna work like this.
我們得談談
We need to talk..
對不起對不起
I am sorry.. I am sorry..
寶貝，你害怕了？
Aww Baby.. You got scared?
一點都不好笑
Arey. It's not funny.
尤吉說
Yogi was saying
艾什就是這麼分手的
Ashish brokeup the same way
他忙於創業
He got busy with the startup
冇時間陪女朋友
he couldn't give time to his girlfriend
胡說八道
What nonsense!
真是陳詞濫調
such a cliche.
但是陳詞濫調的存在是有原因的
But cliches exists for a reason
讓我們來點刺激的？
Let us do some clihe?
我們去果阿吧
Let's go to Goa.
你的班加羅爾之旅怎麼辦？
What about your Bangalore trip?
我不去了
I'll skip it
而且我們甚至不知道這個周末後我們什麼時候有時間
and moreover we dont even know when we get time after this weekend.
別犯傻了
Don't be foolish and
暫時忘掉工作吧
ignore the job.
在接下來的30年裏，就算我不陪著你了，你的工作也會一直伴隨著你
Your job stays with you for the next 30 years, even if I don't
去班加羅爾吧
just go to Bangalore
我們去果阿吧
Lets go to Goa!
It's just a small project, anyway
無論如何，這隻是一個小項目
這是你的工作
Arey, its your work ya
不要欺騙你的工作
Don't cheat your work!
改天再去果阿
Will go to Goa someother time.
好啊，那你以什麼身份去？
Ok. What defines you better?
麥肯錫的商業顧問還是納文·班薩爾的女朋友？
Business Consultant at Mckenzie or Naveen Bansal's girlfirend?
告訴我
Tell me.
好吧
Ok fine.
我去班加羅爾
I will go to Bangalore
高興了吧
Happy?
一點都不浪漫
Very unromantic as*hole
什麼不浪漫啊
What un-romantic as*hole
我們在這裏也可以玩得很開心
We can have fun here as well.
想喝點什麼嗎？
wanna drink something?
一份榛子卡普奇諾和一份雞肉三明治
Ya.. One hazelnut cappucino and one Chicken tikka sandwich
請來一杯茶和兩杯咖啡
One tea and two idlis please.
甜點呢？
and dessert?
你這有什麼煙？
and what cigerrates do you have?
戈德弗雷克，先生
Goldflake. Sir
周三，我畫出了第二幅 FD
I have drawn the second FD too on wednesday.
尤吉正在尋找貸款
Yogi is looking for loan
不知道還要依賴曼達爾多久
and don't know how much to depend on Mandal!
關於加裏的提議
and about Gary's proposal
有時覺得這是必須的
at times feel it's a necessity
有時我又覺得很貪婪
and some times I feel its greed!
但是你不一定要滿足於加裏
But you don't have to necessarily settle for Gary
明天你有個活動
Tomorrow, you have an event
不會有潛在的投資者嗎？
won't there be potential investors?
會有... 但是..
there will be.. But..
也許這是最後一次了
may be for one last time.
我們冇時間了，史瑞雅
We are running out of time, Shreya
如果冇有一個投資者對我們明天的展示感興趣
If none of the investors show any interest in our tommorow's presentation
我們可能隻有加裏這一條路了
we might have to go with Gary
你有冇有試過庭審的方法？
Did you try your Jury room approach?
不，還冇有
No.. not yet.
你的三個合夥人怎麼說？
What do your 3 stooges say?
目前都還冇有說什麼
Nothing as yet
他們指望我做出正確的決定
They are banking on me to take the right decision.
這讓我更害怕了
That's getting me more scared
我現在就可以擁抱你
I could hug you right now
說你會成功的
and say that you will be great
你會做出正確的決定
you will make the right decision
或者
or
我可以不那麼誇張地告訴你
I could be less dramatic and tell you
我相信你 納文巴薩爾
I believe in you Naveen Bansal
和在家裏等你的那三個男孩一樣
Just like the 3 boys waiting for you at home.
哦，該死
Oh Shit!
發生了什麼？
What happened?
等等，等等，我能打包嗎? 6個點心，2杯茶..
wait.. wait.. can I get a parcel..? 6 idli's, 2 chai...
先生，我收攤了
Sir. Food got over.
他怎麼還不回來？
Where is he still?
他說他15分鍾後回來，現在已經兩個小時了
He said he will return in 15 minutes, its been 2 hours now.
叫我等一下喝杯茶
asked me to wait just for a tea.
我得回家睡覺了
I need to go home and sleep
尤基，現在就給他打電話
Yogi, call him now.
他把手機落在這兒了
He left his phone here
我們可以在這裏自己泡茶
we would have made tea here itself
如果這個沙雕冇有把所有的牛奶來凝乳
If this as*hole wouldn't have used all the milk to set the curd
明天是個重要的日子
Tomorrow is an important day
如果我們不吃凝乳和糖，我們怎麼會走運呢？
How do we get lucky if we don't eat curd and sugar?
閉嘴! 你這個廢物
Shut up! You piece of crap
沙雕
As*hole
在過去的6個小時裏，你唯一的作用就是更改了謝謝的字體
For the last 6 hours you are only changing the font of Thank You.
留下一個持久的印象是很重要的
Aey.. Aey.. Its very important to make a lasting impression. Ok!
至少我早上起來冇去城裏閒逛
Atleast I am not roaming around the city since morning
我去印名片了，你這個混蛋
I had been to print visiting cards, you motherf*ckr
當你和投資者見麵時，他們要求聯係你，你會怎麼做？
What do you do when you meet investors and they ask for contacts?
夥計們，這是怎麼回事？
Guys, what's happening here?
納文， 這是辦公室騷擾
Naveen, this is harrasement at work place
我不能這樣工作
I can't work like this.
我不能容忍這種事
I can't tolerate this.
你不能忍受什麼？
What you can't tolerate?
你會把我的筆記本電腦帶到房間然後看著華爾街之狼打飛機
You 'll take my laptop to the room and jerk off watching Wolf of Wallstreet
不，我是在準備演講
No, I was preparing for the pitch.
老子搞死你
I''ll kill you ba*t**d
你知道我在觸摸闆上看到了什麼嗎？
You know what I saw on touchpad?
尤吉，你在說什麼？
Yogi, what are you saying man?
我們都用上了消毒劑，傑圖你跟他說
We had to use sanitizer, Jeetu tell him.
別這樣，尤吉
Stop it.. Stop it Yogi.
尤吉，註意你的年齡
Yogi, Behave your age.
你從10年級開始就在欺負我們
You are bullying us since 10th standard.
別說了
Stop it now.
曼達爾，他說得對，那天觸摸闆上有東西
Madal, he's right. there's was something on the touchpad that day!
傑圖! 你在懷疑我嗎？
Jeetu! You are doubting me?
我發誓，那隻是凝乳
I swear, it was just curd.
傑圖 放鬆
Jeetu relax
我們明天有活動，別緊張
we have an event tomorrow, don't be stressed.
你安靜點
You be quiet.
你知道什麼是壓力嗎？
Do you even know what stress is?
桑亞三天之前想吃西瓜
Soumya is asking for watermelon from past 3 days
我不能買給她是因為
and I am not able to do it because
過去兩天我都在處理一個編譯錯誤
from past 2 days I am getting a compilation error
我已經在這裏待兩天了，已經筋疲力盡了
I am lying here since 2 days and I am exhausted doing this
我想今天好好睡一覺，為明天的活動做好準備
I thought of having a good sleep today to be ready for tomorrow's event
但現在你遲到了兩個小時，把一切都毀了
But now you ruined it by coming two hours late
現在包裏瓦利市場早上6點開市
Now, the market at Borivali opens at 6am
我得去那裏買
I have to buy it from there.
桑亞還要叫我去買新鮮的魚
Soumya will also ask me to get fresh fish also
所以我需要一手拿著西瓜，一手拿著魚
So I need to carry watermelon in one hand and fish in the other
然後從包裏瓦利坐火車
and travel in local train from Borivilli
因為我的自行車輪胎被紮破了
because my bike is punctured and
我冇有時間去修，因為我已經待在這裏兩天了
no time to repair it because I am lying here since the last two days
強調一下
Stress it seems.
接一下
Hold this!
早餐準備好了嗎？
Is breakfast ready?
麻煩快一點
Set it up quickly, please!
你看到我的信息了嗎？
Did you read my message?
我還冇時間看
I don't have time now
我已經遲到半小時了
I am already runing late by half an hour
我得收拾一下趕緊走了
I have to get fresh and leave.
星期天早上你要去哪兒，孩子？
Where are you going on Sunday morning, son?
爸爸
Dad!
不是的，我侄子說
Arey No.. my nephew was saying
維斯瓦納坦 · 阿南德根本不喜歡油炸伊德利
Vishwanathan Anand doesn't like fried idli at all
什麼？
What?
說真的
Ya seriously
人太多了
Too much crowd..
這些二十四五歲的孩子一畢業就想開公司
These 24-25 years kids try to start the company as soon as they get out of college.
他們中的一半甚至可能都不知道企業家怎麼拚寫
Half of them might not even know the spelling of entreprenuer
都是弟弟
All virgin as*es!
那個女孩看起來比較小
That qeue looks smaller.
這裏是在排隊簽到嗎？
Is this the line for Registration?
不
No!
我們在這等著領通行證
We are standing to pick up the ration
哈哈哈
hahaha
一幫沙雕
As*hole
你認識他嗎？
Do you know him?
誰？
whom?
他叫阿米特·阿瓦斯蒂，那家夥想成為紮克伯格
That guy. Wanna be Zukerburg, Amit Awasti.
在哈莫爾佈爾計算機學院拿到的工學學位
completed his B-Tech from NIT Hamirpur
卻穿著哈沃德T恤炫耀
but wears Harward T-shit to show-off
他是"訴訟律師"的創始人
He is the founder of Litigator
訴訟律師？
Litigator?
一個律師的社交網絡app
Its the social network for Lawyers.
去年3月，他們與聯合創始人就股權問題發生了爭執
They had issues with co-founder regarding equity last March
他們用他自己的應用程序對他提起訴訟
They used his own app to file a lawsuit against him
你認識他嗎？
Do you recognise him?
誰? 囧雪？
who? John Snow?
什麼雪？
who Snow?
那個穿黑西裝的家夥？
That guy in black suit?
黑西裝
Oh..the guy in black suit?
對
Ya.
嗯
haan.
不認識
No.
他是送奶網站的創始人 裏特維克·穆赫吉
He is the founder of milkman.com, Ritwik mukherjee.
哦哦
Okay.
送奶工我聽說過它就像乳製品的優步
Milkman. I've heard about it. Its like the Uber of dairy products
乳製品個屁
Dairy products my ass !
那是一個在線馬廄
Its just an online stable.
2012年，它的名字是 dudhwala. com..
In 2012, it started of with the name dudhwala.com...
但後來政府以為它是色情網站，就禁止了它
but then government banned it thinking it's a porn website.
現在他們用一個新的名字重新啓動了它
Now they have relaunched it with a new name.
順便說一下，我是索拉佈 · 曼達爾
By the way, I'm Saurabh Mandal.
這是納文 巴薩爾
This is Naveen Bansal
還有尤吉
And yogi.
你好，先生
Hello sir.
你有 VC 嗎？
Do you have a VC ?
名片？
Visiting card ?
有有有，剛印好的
Yes, I do. Freshly baked .
那就交換一下吧
Then give it.
事實上，在這樣的場合中你會遇到很多欺詐行為
Actually you meet a lot of frauds in such events.
上次有個混蛋拍了一張自拍，說“我是拉胡爾 · 亞達夫”
Last time some asshole clicked a selfie saying "I am Rahul Yadav".
後來我才知道那個混蛋是個學生
Later I got to know that asshole was just a B.com student from Mithibhai.
用兩隻手遞名片，一隻手不禮貌
Give it using two hands... With one hand is cnsidered unluncky!
我們都是同齡人，這些應該不用我告訴你的
You should be knowing all of this, we are of same age.
拿著
Take it.
對，就像這樣
ya.. like that
拉維 · 拉斯托吉
Ravi Ram Rastogi.
嗯
Hmm..
首席執行官、首席技術官、首席營銷官
CEO, CTO, CMO
Superentreprenuer.com 創始人
Founder, Superentreprenuer.com
這是我的第八家公司
This is my 8th company
在這之前的那七家呢？
and about those seven before this?
都倒閉了
They were shut down.
哦
Oh!
但是這一次我將進入財富500強
But this one will take me to the list of Fortune 500
等著瞧吧
Wait and Watch!
事情是... 聽好了
Thing is.. Hello..
事情是這樣的
So the thing is
企業家的靈魂總是不安分的
The soul of entreprenuer is always restless.
它會一直遊蕩，直到你想出一個傑作
It will roaming around untill you come up with a masterpiece.
這麼說隻有你們三個？
So only 3 of you guys?
不，先生
No sir..
不，不，很好
No.. no. Its good.
聯合創始人數量越少，股權價值就越高
The lesser number of co-founders, higher will be the equity value.
不，先生，我們有四個人，傑圖正在來的路上
No sir, we are four of us. Jeetu is on his way
尤吉，打電話問他在哪裏？
Yogi, call him and ask where did he reach?
好吧 那就是8% 的損失
Oho.. that's like 8% loss.
冇問題，繼續
No problem, carry on!
算了吧，爸爸
Leave it Dad.
在保修期內
It's in the warranty
公司的人會免費來修的
company guy will come and fix it for free.
你學的是計算機科學而不是機械
haan. You studied computer science instead of mechanical
你可能會厭倦做這些事情
you might get tired to do all these stuffs
給我一個更大的螺絲刀？
give me a bigger screw driver?
尤吉：你在哪裏
你手機裏有螺絲刀嗎？
are you looking for app for it?
不，不，是關於工作的
No.. no. Its about work
瓦欽說
Watchen was saying..
你兩天冇回家了
You didn't come home for 2 days.
是這樣的，爸爸
Actually Dad.
公司的人讓他加班
the company guys are making him work a lot
因為這個項目
beacuse of the project
他們每天都給他打電話，星期天都不讓休息
they call him daily, even on sundays
你去收拾一下
You get fresh
準備好
get ready
爸爸，你想吃西瓜嗎？
Dad, would you want to eat watermelon?
你們星期天有什麼項目？
What kind of project do you have on Sunday's?
打電話告訴你老闆
Call your boss and tell
你爸爸從比卡內爾來看你，所以今天不能加班
your dad has come from Bikaner, so can't come today.
把電話給我，讓我跟你老闆說
give the phone, let me speak to him
爸爸，事情不是這樣的
Dad, It doesn't work that way.
我隻待一天
have just come for a day
如果不是為了潘迪亞吉女兒的婚禮
If not for Pandyaji's daughter wedding
我才不來
I wouldn't have come.
你就不能和你爸爸吃個午飯嗎
Can't you have lunch with your dad for a day
冇有你，你的公司不會倒閉的
your company won't shut down without you.
現在翅膀這麼硬了嗎
Yu have grown up now right!
不是那樣的，爸爸
nothing like that Dad.
我馬上回來
I will just be back.
嘿! 我在跟你說話呢
Hey! I am talking to you!
給你老闆回複一句等會再說
Send TTYL to your boss
爸爸
Dad
西瓜
Watermelon
餵，尤吉
Hello Yogi.
尤吉，我不能去了
Yogi i can't come
我爸突然來我家了
All of a sudden dad showed up!
什麼?
What nonsense?!
是的! 他不讓我走
yes! He is not allowing me to leave.
不讓走？
Not allowing to leave?
你是四年級學生嗎？
Are you a 4th grader?
唉……尤吉
Arey Yogi.
傑圖？
Jeetu?
好的，爸爸，我來了
Yes dad i am coming.
我在說重要的事，你卻在撒尿?
I am talking something important, and you are peeing?!
等等吧，尤吉
Just wait Yogi.
傑圖？
Jeetu?
研討會快結束了，午餐後的活動很關鍵
The seminar is about end, post lunch is our main event.
快點過來
Leave quickly!
尤吉，我一會兒再和你談
Yogi I will talk to you later
傑圖？
Jeetu?
是的，爸爸
yes dad!
這是什麼？
What is this?
看起來像一條內褲
looks like a boxer
它卡在水箱後麵了
it was stuck behind the tank
你都冇有時間檢查下洗了多少衣服嗎
You don't even have time to keep your clothes in check.
你在洗手間幹什麼？
and what were you doimg in the bathroom?
冇什麼，電話..
nothing.. phone...
我在小便
I was peeing.
小便之後你要洗手
you will wash your hands after that or
不然公司的人都會開始不洗手
anyone from the company will come to do it.
真的非常抱歉，但這是我第四次告訴您
I'm really really sorry sir, but this is the fourth time i'm telling you
除非團隊人到齊了，否則我不能給你們通行證
that i can not give you the passes until the entire team registered
但是你總得讓我們創業啊
But madam you have to let us startup
這是我們的名片
This is our VC card
對不起，先生，我們必須遵守一些規定
I am sorry sir. We have to follow certain guidelines.
聽著
See, listen...
阿普爾瓦
Apoorva..
阿普爾瓦，我們的朋友在路上了
Apoorva, our friend is on his way.
難道不能先給我們三張通行證嗎
Isn't it possible to first give us our three passes.
朋友的通行證等他到了你再給他
Like, you can hold on to our friend's pass.
他到的時候來找你拿
He will collect it from you, when he is here.
讓我看看
Let me check.
納文
Naveen.
納文……
Naveen..
其實我
Actually I
剛剛發現..
just found out that...
這裏不是電影院
this is not a movie theatre...
我們不能幫忙保管通行證
and we cannot hold on to your passes.
但是我們已經付了註冊費..
But we have paid the registration fee....
每人1857盧比
1,857 Rupees per head.
先生，麻煩你靠邊站
Sir, you're holding the que, could you please step aside.
你不能這樣對我們..
You can't do this to us...
你找你領導出來
I want to speak to the management.
她怎麼能這樣跟我們說話？
How can she talk to us like this ?
我會讓你被炒魷魚的
I'll get you fired.
記住我的話
Mark my words.
戰鬥才剛剛開始
The battle has just begun.
一場1857盧比的戰爭
The battle of 1,857 rupees.
諸神不會放過她的
Mangal and Pandey wont let her be.
別說了
Stop it.
什麼人啊
What rubbish !
她怎麼能這樣跟我們說話
How can she talk to us like this.
放鬆
Relax.
讓我們想想辦法
Let's figure out something.
還有什麼辦法？
Figure out what?
她有每個人的檔案
She has everyone's profiles.
傑圖不來我們就進不去
We won't get entry without jitu
早就說了，走之前我們應該吃點糖和豆腐吧
I told you, let's have sugar and curd before leaving.
曼達爾，你快別bb了
Mandal, Please don't start again.
不要回答
Dont' answer.
回答
Answer.
嗨，加裏
Hi Gary..
加裏，我現在有點忙，過會兒我再打電話給你行嗎？
Gary, I am little busy, can I call you after sometime ?
演講還冇開始呢
There's still time for the presentation to start, Parth..
你就已經開始忙了？
You're already busy ?
不是，我冇有，加裏
No Gary.
我們隻是來看朋友的
We just came here to see a friend.
在這種場合不會遇到朋友
One doesn't meet friends in such events...
你要麼遇到競爭對手，要麼遇到投資者
You either meet your competition or investors!
別把我當傻瓜
Don't think of me as an idiot.
聽著
And Listen..
你把免提打開
Put your phone on loudspeaker
這樣你就不用比劃了
Then you won't have to play Dumb charades.
好
Ya.
我冇有生氣..
I'm not upset...
如果我是你，我也會這麼做的
If I was in your place I would have done the same.
你應該為你們的産品爭取一個好價錢
You should get a good value for a good product..
冇有比這更好的地方來實現你的産品價值了
and there is no better place then such events to realize your product's value.
加裏，這是個好活動，但是我們..
Gary, It is a good event but we're.....
趕時間? 我知道
In a hurry ? I know..
你得見很多投資者..
You have to meet a lot of investors...
討論一下你們的未來計劃
have to discuss you're future plans
我知道
I know..
但在那之前，你不想聽聽我的新提議嗎？
But before that, you dont want to listen to my new offer ?
新的提議？
New offer ?
我想了很多
I thought a lot..
然後我意識到這筆交易對你們有點不公平
Then I realised that this deal is little unfair for you..
所以我們這樣，在你們的報價後麵……
So the amount which you guys had proposed?
加一個零
Suffix a zero to the number.
加裏
Gary..
那可是一大筆錢
That's a lot of money!
冇錯
No.
你想要很多錢..
You wanted a lot of money...
我現在就給你錢，十倍哦
and I am giving you a lot of money X 10
但是當然..
But ofcourse...
股本將是相同的... 51%
Equity will be the same... 51%.
這冇有商量的餘地
That is non-negotiable.
我正要去我的羅納瓦拉農捨
I'm on my way to my lonavala farmhouse...
參加會議
For a meeting.
在我到達之前給我你的答案..
Give me your answer before I get there...
否則交易取消
Or the offer stands cancelled.
另外……
And ya...
如果你在那之前找到投資者的話……
If you get an investor before that then..
祝你一切順利
All the best.
但是加裏，我怎麼能這麼快回複你呢
But Gary how will I reply so fast
納文，你是啤酒
Naveen you're beer
而我是蛇
And I am snakcs!
如果我們兩個聚在一起，會很熱鬨的
If we both get together, we'll have a party!
我會等你的電話..
I'll be waiting for your call...
帕斯
Parth.
他剛才是不是給我們……
Did he just offer us...
在這樣的關鍵時刻，傑圖總是不見蹤影
Jitu always goes missing in such crucial times.
曼達爾再給他發一次短信-好的
Mandal just text him once. -okay.
你怎麼想
What are you thinking ?
我需要一個陪審室
I need a jury room.
聞起來真香
Smells nice!
你加味精了嗎？
Have you added ajwaine?
是的，爸爸
Yes papa.
海魚有一種很獨特的味道
Salt water fish have a very unique taste..
很柔軟
They're very soft soft.
是啊
ya.
我們那就吃不到
We don't get it over at our place!
加裏提出10倍價格收購我們的項目，他要馬上給答複，給我回電話快點
我兩分鍾後回來
I'll be back in two minutes.
吃著飯呢你要去哪裏？
Where are you going at lunch time ?
就在附近買點牛奶... 樓下
Just closeby to get some milk... Rgiht below the building!
送牛奶的早上已經來了
The milkman has already come in the morning!
爸爸，我想我晚上會給你準備一些拉比
Dad. I though I'll prepare some 'Rabdi' for you in the evening!
牛奶少了，所以我讓他去買
There was less milk so I asked him to.
是的，她讓我這麼做的
Ya she asked me to.
但是你為什麼要在這麼熱的天氣裏出去呢？
But why do you need to go in this heat???
我下次會吃的
I will have it next time.
不，爸爸，不麻煩，我堅持
No Dad. It's no trouble. I insist.
桑婭做的臘腸很好吃，我2分鍾就回來
Saumya makes nice 'rabdi'. I'll go get it in 2.
等一下，傑圖
Wait a minute Jitu.
回來坐下
Sit over here.
閨女過來
Beta (daughter) listen.
去把這藥給我煎了
Make me this concoction.
爸爸，我可以在午飯後去嗎？
Papa, can I make it after lunch ?
不行，醫生讓我午飯時吃
No, the doctor has asked me to have it with lunch.
聽好了
And listen.
慢慢來，慢慢煮
Take your time and boil it for long!
不用著急
There's no hurry.
好的，爸爸
Yes, Papa.
老實告訴我
Tell me honestly.
你要去哪裏
Where were you going.
爸爸，去買牛奶，還有什麼
Papa, to buy milk, whatelse.
你是要去抽煙吧
You were going to smoke a ciggarette.
爸爸，我在大學裏就戒煙了
Papa, I quit smoking in college.
不要撒謊
Don't lie.
我在你公文包裏找到了幾根煙
I've found a few in your office bag!
爸爸
Papa..
我還要為你撒多少謊？
How much should I lie for you ?
在你結婚前..
Before marriage...
結婚前，我不得不對帕瑞瑪撒謊說你不喝酒也不抽煙
Before marriage I had to lie to Parimal that you dont drink or smoke..
他們把女兒嫁到我們家是因為他們信任我們
They married their daughter into our family because they had trust in us.
你也答應過你媽媽
And you had promised your mom
你會戒煙
That you would quit smoking!
你戒了嗎？
Did you quit?
好吧，對不起，爸爸
Okay, Sorry papa.
如果你真的想抽煙，那就嚼口香糖吧
If you get desperate to smoke than have a chewing gum .
哈迪亞爾就是這樣戒煙的
Hardiyal quit it the same way.
好吧，爸爸，那我去樓下買點薄荷糖來
Okay Papa then I will go, get some mint from downstairs!
給你
Here.
拿去吧
Have it.
如果你再發出一點聲音
If you make one more sound
我會把機油倒你嘴裏讓你漱口
I will put castrol in your mouth and make you gargle it.
我們還在等什麼？
What are we waiting for ?
我們已經賺翻了
We are getting soo much money now!
如果我們繼續拖時間，那這些錢就冇了
If we take more time then even this plan will get ruined.
納文有做決定的權利
Naveen has the first right to take a decision.
等他從陪審室出來
Let him come out of the jury room.
然後我們再做決定
Then we will decide.
這個陪審室是幹什麼的？
What is this jury room ?
我從大學時就看他這樣做過
I've been sseing it since our college time.
每當納文麵對睏境時
Whenever Naveen faces a dilema
他會把自己鎖在房間裏15分鍾
He locks himself in a room for 15 minutes.
然後做出正確的決定
And he comes out with the right decision.
這就是為什麼我們稱之為陪審室
And thats why we call it a jury room.
但是在這種場合，他是怎麼找到空房間的呢？
But in such a busy event, how did he find a empty room ?
這是典型的性別歧視
This is the height of sexism.
難道他們根本就不想讓女性企業家來嗎？
What, were they not expecting female entreprenuers at all ?
男廁所開著，但女廁所卻鎖著
Gents washroom is open but the female washroom is locked!
在這樣的比賽中你碰到很多這樣的事情
You will get a lot of mcps in such events.
你知道嗎
You know what..
甚至在我的名片上印的都是我兄弟的電話號碼
Even in my visiting card I have given my brothers number.
你是怎麼做到的？
And how did you ?
如果一百塊能夠說服英國人... ..
If one Gandhiji can convice lacks of britishers ...
為什麼二百塊不能說服保潔員
Why wouldn't a housekeeper get convinced with two!
你們還在這兒？
You guys are still here ?
是啊
Ya.
冇回家？
Didn't go home?
你們公司的 CEO 在哪裏？
Where is that CEO of your's ?
我們正在等他
Actually that's who we are waiting for!
如果你有時間的話
If you're wasting time...
那就在推特上關註我吧
Then follow me on twitter!
好啊
Ya ya..
我有198個粉絲
I have 198 followers.
如果你們兩個都關註我，那麼那就破二百了
If you both follow me, then it'll become a double century.
媽的
Shit !
我隻有116個粉..
I have only 116...
但是我在領英上有312個粉絲
But I have 312 followers on linkedIn.
312？
312 ?
媽的
Shit !
等我的應用程序發佈
Just wait for my app to get launched..
看我怎麼追上你
Then watch how I overtake you.
你為什麼不去那邊交朋友呢？
Why can't you go there and do your networking ?
其實我在等我的室友
Actually I am waiting for my roommate..
I forgot my keys.
我忘帶鑰匙了
其他七個人都被淘汰了
Even the other 7 are out.
他是來給我送鑰匙的
So he is coming to give me the keys.
你們是9個人住在一起嗎？
You'll are 9 people staying together?
四居室？
4 BHK ?
不不
No No..
兩居室
It's a 2 BHK
但空間足夠大
But spacious enough.
74平
800 sqft.
其實
Actually
自從我2008年離婚後..
Since I got a divorced in 2008...
我就不得不住在合租房裏
I've to live in a shared apartment!
這樣可以建立
It helps you build..
團隊精神
Teamspirit.
你離婚了？
You had a divorce ?
是的
Yes.
對不起
Sorry.
你為什麼說對不起？
Why you're saying sorry ?
當她不說對不起的時候
When she is not saying sorry..
你為什麼說對不起？
Why you're saying sorry ?
冇關係
It's okay.
並不是每個人的婚姻都那麼完美
Everyone is not that lucky to have a Sudhamurthi in their life.
等我的公司拿到融資
Once my company gets funded...
老子一天換一個女朋友
Just wait and watch how 'Manglik' girls line up for me!
但是這麼多年來，你一次融資也冇拿到？
But in so many years you didn't get funded even once ?
也不是……
I did..
2003年的時候
In 2003 I did..
有一個投資者準備投我
There was an investor who was ready to invest..
但是要求50% 的股權
But was asking for 50% equity.
但是我們的創始人兼首席執行官
And our founder and CEO
有點像佛祖
Was sort of a buddha type..
他拒絕了
Said no to it .
從那以後直到今天... 我嚮上帝發誓
Since then till today... I swear to god
我唯一一次睡安穩覺的時候是在火車的臥鋪車廂裏
The only time I have slept peacefully is while travelling in a train's sleeper class.
餵
Ya karunesh..
Yes.
是的
進來吧
Come inside.
什麼
What !
他們不讓你進？
They aren't letting you?
你為什麼總是穿短褲出門？
Why do you always come in boxers???
笨蛋
Dumbfuck!
怎麼了？
What happened ?
說話啊？
Tell me what happened ?
尤吉？
Yogi ?
我已經決定了
Okay, I have decided.
什麼？
What ?
我想等人齊了再說，我們一起去傑圖家吧
I want to tell you'll with Jeetu. Let's go to his place .
你在幹什麼？
What are you doing ?
尤吉給我發短信了，我得下去一趟
Yogi'd texted me. I am going down.
他們在停車場等我
They are waiting for me in the parking lot.
如果爸爸醒了，我該怎麼辦？
What will I answer dad if he gets up ?
拖2分鍾就好
Please handle it for 2mins..
求你了
Please..
Please.
好吧，你去吧
Okay, you go...
我拖住他
I will handle it.
他家三樓還是四樓？
Third floor or fourth floor ?
來了
Terrace !
別在這站著...-嘿，傑圖
Don't stand... -Hey jitu, hie..
不要站在這裏，這裏的保安是我爸爸的間諜
Don't stand over here, the watchman out here is my dad's spy.
- 你怎麼決定的?-曼達爾，把聲音調小點
Hmm, so what did you decide? Mandal, lower the volume.
你怎麼決定的，我們拿加裏的錢，對吧？
So what did you decide, we are taking money from Gary, right ?
這家夥什麼都冇告訴我們
This one's not telling us anything at all!
不，我們不拿他的錢
No, we aren't taking money from Gary.
事實上我已經給他發短信說”不”了
Infact I already texted him saying "No".
納文，這個決定背後的邏輯是什麼？
Naveen, what is the logic behind this ?
什麼邏輯，這是我們的想法，我們的努力
What logic, It's our idea our hardwork
我們花了這麼長的時間來研究它
We are working on it from such a long time
現在怎麼可以隨意的把一半股權給別人？
Now randomly we would give away half the stakes to somebody, why ?
他給我們錢啊，這就是為什麼，你還不明白嗎
He is giving us money, that's why, don't you get it..
這對我們公司的估值有很大幫助啊
How it helps our compnay's valuation!
我嚮你保證，在一年內我們能創造更多的價值
I guarantee you, in one year we will create more value than this .
納文
Naveen..
你是認真的嗎
Are you serious !
我們甚至都不能參加今天的活動了
We couldn't even go for today's event
別想募集資金了
Forget about raising funds...
投資者絕不會打電話給我們第二次機會
Investors aren't calling us for even a second meeting.
你認為金主爸爸們會來……
You think Sikoya and Nexus will join hands...
求你接受他們的投資嗎
and beg you to take their investments ? !
We'lll have to compromise a little, Naveen .
我們得妥協一下，納文
你們難道冇有意識到這個家夥是一個卑鄙的商人
Aren't you all realising that thios guy is a 'Bhujiyawaala'.
他甚至冇有技術背景
He doesn't even have a technical background..
他將會如何理解我們的産品？
How will he understand our product ?
這是優勢啊
That's the advantage.
如果他冇有任何技術背景
If he doesn't have any technical knowledge
他就不會幹涉的-如果他幹涉呢？
he won't interfere . -what if he interferes ?
那我們就完了
Then we're fucked.
我們以後再考慮這個問題
We'll think about it later..
你怎麼能獨自做出如此重要的決定呢？
And how can you take such an important decision by yourself?
就因為你的名片上寫著總裁
Just because you've C.E.O. on your visiting card...
並不意味著你就是老闆
... doesn't mean you are the boss.
納文
Naveen
我們是一個團隊
We are a team..
但是團隊裏冇有我
And there is no I in team.
兄弟們，不是這樣的
Guys it isn't that..
每次我在陪審室裏做出決定都是正確的
You know, whenever I've taken a decision in the jury room, it's always been right
是嗎？
yes？
你在陪審室裏到底是怎麼做的？
And what exactly do you do in the jury room ?
什麼？
What ?
我在問你
I am asking you!
你在陪審室裏是怎麼做決定的？
How do you take your decision in the jury room?
這很簡單
It's simple..
He must be listing down the pros and cons..
他一定是在列舉利弊
對其進行 SWAT 分析並確定可行性
Does a SWAT analysis of it and determines the probablity.
我在高中的時候也這樣做過
Even I have done that in the third semester of my high school
SWAT分析？
SWAT analysis ?..
可行性？
Probablity ?..
他他媽的扔了一枚硬幣然後就定了
He fucking tosses a coin and decides.
什麼
What !
就這樣？
Tosses and decides ?
納文，看著我
Naveen look here..
當年我娶桑亞的時候就是讓你做的決定啊！！
I had decided to marry saumya after asking you!
我不需要擲硬幣來決定
I didn't need to toss a coin for that.
但是你今天就需要？
But you needed it today?
你他媽的用硬幣決定了
You fucking decided four peoples carrer,ambition
四個人的事業，野心和未來！
and their future on the basis of tossing a coin !
如果是硬幣的另一麵呢？
And what if it was the other side of the coin ?
那麼我們現在是不是應該在加裏的農捨拍他馬屁?
Then right now we would have been in Gary's farmhouse licking his ass ? !
納文，你要下地獄我都跟你，但我不能跟隨1盧比的硬幣
Naveen I can follow you till hell but I can't follow a 1 Rupee coin.
納文我們都辭職了
Naveen, everyone has left their job...
這家創業公司是你的主意，對吧？
This startup was your idea, right ?
我們在你家每天連續工作16個小時
We are working 16 hrs continously at your home.
然而這位首席執行官擲硬幣做決定
And this CEO tosses a coin and decides.
至少你可以問我們一次？
Atleast you could have asked us once ?
這對你來說很難嗎
Was that asking for too much from you?
你投出來的是什麼? 正麵還是反麵?-我不知道
What was it Naveen? Head or tail ? - Guys I don't know what it was!
作出決定依據是拋硬幣的過程，而不是拋硬幣的結果
Decision was taken on the basis of tossing the coin, not on the result of it.
什麼意思？
What do you mean ?
就像這枚硬幣，生活給了我們兩個選擇..
Like this coin even life gives us 2 choices...
不管你列出多少贊成和反對的理由，雙方的幾率一定是平等的
No matter how many lists of pros and cons you make both sides would always be equal
而且你無法做出選擇
And you won't be able to pick any side.
這時你能做的就是傾聽你的心聲
That time all you can do is listen to your heart.
這就是為什麼如果你隻拋一次硬幣，你就會知道哪一麵朝上
That's why if you toss the coin once, you will come to know which side won.
但是你還冇看到它是正還是反？
But you didn't even see if it was a head or a tail ?
我不用看，已經聽到了
I didnt see it but I heard it.
當硬幣在空中的時候
When the coin stays in the air for half a second..
一個聲音從你的心底傳來……
A voice answers from the bottom of your heart...
說道：
Which says..
是正麵，是正麵
Please let it be heads, please heads!
這時你就會意識到不管硬幣是正麵還是反麵
That's when you realize no matter what the result is...
你的內心希望它是正麵的
Your heart wants it to be heads.
我意識到我們的第一筆投資不能建立在貪婪的基礎上
And I have realised that our first investment can't be set on the basis of greed.
加裏貪圖公平，而我們貪圖錢財
Where gary is in greed of equity and we of money
我們的第一筆投資應該是基於我們的..
Our first investment should be only on the basis of our...
創意與技術
Idea and skill.
如果隻是因為錢，那我不能讓任何人控製我的野心
Just for more funding I can't let anyone control my ambitions.
我真的很抱歉我不能這麼做
I am really sorry I could'nt do it.
現在你們想怎麼辦
Now you guys decide what to do.
我們要去哪兒？
Where are we going ?
回去繼續參加活動
Back to the event.
但是如果他們不讓我們進去呢
But what if they don't let us in!
那就用我們的一貫操作
The same thing what we always do ..
試試
Try.
我們走
Let's go.